(self.webpackChunk_N_E=self.webpackChunk_N_E||[]).push([[743],{6181:(e,t,s)=>{Promise.resolve().then(s.bind(s,7524))},7030:(e,t,s)=>{"use strict";s.d(t,{A:()=>r});var i=s(5155),n=s(7825),o=s(2051),a=s(1640);function r(){return(0,i.jsxs)("footer",{className:"mt-6 text-center text-gray-400 text-sm",children:[(0,i.jsxs)("p",{className:"mb-2",children:["Created by ",(0,i.jsx)("a",{className:"text-cyan-300",target:"_blank",href:"https://www.purutuladhar.com",children:"Puru Tuladhar"})," â€“ Sharpen your skills and keep learning!"]}),(0,i.jsxs)("a",{href:"https://tally.so/r/3N4O8W",target:"_blank",className:"text-underline",children:["Leave a ",(0,i.jsx)("span",{className:"text-cyan-300",children:"feedback"})]})," | ",(0,i.jsxs)("a",{href:"https://patreon.com/puru",target:"_blank",className:"",children:["Support me on ",(0,i.jsx)("span",{className:"text-cyan-300",children:"Patreon"})]}),(0,i.jsx)("br",{}),(0,i.jsx)("br",{}),(0,i.jsxs)("div",{className:"flex justify-center space-x-4",children:[(0,i.jsx)("a",{href:"https://twitter.com/ptuladhar3",target:"_blank",rel:"noopener noreferrer",className:"text-gray-400 hover:text-cyan-400 transition-colors duration-300","aria-label":"",children:(0,i.jsx)(n.A,{size:24})}),(0,i.jsx)("a",{href:"https://www.linkedin.com/in/ptuladhar3/",target:"_blank",rel:"noopener noreferrer",className:"text-gray-400 hover:text-cyan-400 transition-colors duration-300","aria-label":"",children:(0,i.jsx)(o.A,{size:24})}),(0,i.jsx)("a",{href:"https://github.com/tuladhar",target:"_blank",rel:"noopener noreferrer",className:"text-gray-400 hover:text-cyan-400 transition-colors duration-300","aria-label":"",children:(0,i.jsx)(a.A,{size:24})})]})]})}},6708:(e,t,s)=>{"use strict";function i(e){for(let t=e.length-1;t>0;t--){let s=Math.floor(Math.random()*(t+1));[e[t],e[s]]=[e[s],e[t]]}return e}s.d(t,{A:()=>i})},7524:(e,t,s)=>{"use strict";s.r(t),s.d(t,{default:()=>y});var i=s(5155),n=s(8803),o=s.n(n),a=s(2115),r=s(5683),c=s(6899),l=s(3239),u=s(5340),d=s(5565),m=s(4918),p=s(7030),g=s(6708);let h=[{question:"What are the '4Cs' of Cloud Native Security?",options:["Container, Code, Cluster, Cloud","Compliance, Cloud, Code, Controls","Compute, Cluster, Configuration, Compliance","Cluster, Cloud, Code, Compliance"],correctAnswers:["Container, Code, Cluster, Cloud"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which of the following best describes the concept of 'Infrastructure Security' in cloud environments?",options:["Securing physical hardware only","Ensuring data is encrypted at rest","Protecting against unauthorized access to cloud resources","Implementing firewalls at the network level"],correctAnswers:["Protecting against unauthorized access to cloud resources"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What is a primary goal of using controls and frameworks in cloud security?",options:["To increase application performance","To standardize security practices across environments","To enhance user experience","To reduce costs associated with cloud services"],correctAnswers:["To standardize security practices across environments"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which isolation technique is commonly used to separate workloads in Kubernetes?",options:["Namespaces","Virtual Machines","Load Balancers","Service Meshes"],correctAnswers:["Namespaces"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What is the purpose of an artifact repository in cloud native security?",options:["To store application logs","To manage source code versions","To store and manage container images securely","To provide a backup for databases"],correctAnswers:["To store and manage container images securely"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"'Image scanning' in the context of artifact repositories is primarily used for what purpose?",options:["To optimize image size for faster deployment","To identify vulnerabilities within container images","To ensure compliance with licensing agreements","To manage user access to images"],correctAnswers:["To identify vulnerabilities within container images"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"'Least privilege' is a principle that applies to which aspect of workload security?",options:["User access management","Network configuration","Data encryption methods","Application performance monitoring"],correctAnswers:["User access management"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"'Runtime security' primarily focuses on which of the following?",options:["Securing code during development","Monitoring applications during execution for vulnerabilities","Establishing secure coding practices","Auditing past security incidents"],correctAnswers:["Monitoring applications during execution for vulnerabilities"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"'Network segmentation' in Kubernetes helps to achieve what goal?",options:["Improving application performance","Isolating different parts of an application to enhance security","Reducing costs associated with network traffic","Simplifying application deployment"],correctAnswers:["Isolating different parts of an application to enhance security"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"'Configuration management' tools are important for which aspect of cloud native security?",options:["Ensuring consistent deployment of applications","Managing user permissions effectively","Encrypting sensitive data at rest","Monitoring network traffic for anomalies"],correctAnswers:["Ensuring consistent deployment of applications"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which framework is commonly used for assessing cloud security compliance?",options:["ISO/IEC 27001","NIST Cybersecurity Framework","COBIT","All of the above"],correctAnswers:["All of the above"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What does 'shared responsibility model' refer to in cloud computing?",options:["The division of security tasks between the provider and customer","The requirement for customers to manage all aspects of their infrastructure","The concept that all users are responsible for their own data","The need for collaboration between different teams within an organization"],correctAnswers:["The division of security tasks between the provider and customer"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"In Kubernetes, what does 'RBAC' stand for?",options:["Resource-Based Access Control","Remote-Based Access Control","Role-Based Access Control","Role-Bound Access Control"],correctAnswers:["Role-Based Access Control"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which isolation technique can be utilized to prevent unauthorized access to sensitive data in Kubernetes?",options:["Network Policies","Service Accounts","Ingress Controllers","Load Balancers"],correctAnswers:["Network Policies"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What is a common vulnerability found in container images that can be mitigated through scanning?",options:["Lack of user permissions","Inconsistent coding practices","Insecure default configurations","Inadequate logging"],correctAnswers:["Insecure default configurations"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What does 'container orchestration' primarily help with in terms of workload security?",options:["Easier deployment and scaling of applications","Increased data redundancy","Simplified user authentication","Enhanced network traffic management"],correctAnswers:["Easier deployment and scaling of applications"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What is the primary purpose of using a service mesh in cloud native applications?",options:["To manage container orchestration","To enhance security and observability of service-to-service communications","To automate application deployment","To provide a centralized logging system"],correctAnswers:["To enhance security and observability of service-to-service communications"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which of the following is a key benefit of using secrets management in Kubernetes?",options:["Improving application performance","Storing sensitive data securely and managing access to it","Reducing the size of container images","Automating deployment processes"],correctAnswers:["Storing sensitive data securely and managing access to it"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What does 'container hardening' involve?",options:["Optimizing container performance","Reducing the attack surface by minimizing vulnerabilities in container images","Increasing the size of container images for better performance","Automating the deployment of containers"],correctAnswers:["Reducing the attack surface by minimizing vulnerabilities in container images"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"'Pod Security Policies' in Kubernetes are used to enforce what kind of security controls?",options:["Network traffic restrictions","Resource allocation limits","Security contexts for pods, such as running as non-root users","Access control for Kubernetes API"],correctAnswers:["Security contexts for pods, such as running as non-root users"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which of the following is a common practice for securing cloud provider infrastructure?",options:["Regularly updating and patching systems","Using only public cloud services without any security measures","Disabling all logging features to enhance performance","Avoiding multi-factor authentication"],correctAnswers:["Regularly updating and patching systems"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"'Zero Trust' architecture emphasizes which of the following principles?",options:["'Trust but verify' approach to network security","'Never trust, always verify' regardless of location or user identity","'Trust is established once and maintained indefinitely'","'Only trusted users can access all resources'"],correctAnswers:["'Never trust, always verify' regardless of location or user identity"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What is the role of 'audit logs' in cloud native security?",options:["To improve application performance by reducing overhead.","To track and record access and changes to resources for compliance and security monitoring.","To manage user permissions effectively.","To automate backup processes."],correctAnswers:["To track and record access and changes to resources for compliance and security monitoring."],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which tool is commonly used for continuous security monitoring in cloud environments?",options:["Kubernetes Dashboard","AWS CloudTrail","Docker Compose","Kubelet"],correctAnswers:["AWS CloudTrail"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which of the following is a key benefit of using secrets management in Kubernetes?",options:["Improving application performance","Storing sensitive data securely and managing access to it","Reducing the size of container images","Automating deployment processes"],correctAnswers:["Storing sensitive data securely and managing access to it"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What does 'container hardening' involve?",options:["Optimizing container performance","Increasing the size of container images for better performance","Reducing the attack surface by minimizing vulnerabilities in container images","Automating the deployment of containers"],correctAnswers:["Reducing the attack surface by minimizing vulnerabilities in container images"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"'Pod Security Policies' in Kubernetes are used to enforce what kind of security controls?",options:["Network traffic restrictions","Resource allocation limits","Access control for Kubernetes API","Security contexts for pods, such as running as non-root users"],correctAnswers:["Security contexts for pods, such as running as non-root users"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which of the following is a common practice for securing cloud provider infrastructure?",options:["Regularly updating and patching systems","Using only public cloud services without any security measures","Disabling all logging features to enhance performance","Avoiding multi-factor authentication"],correctAnswers:["Regularly updating and patching systems"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"'Zero Trust' architecture emphasizes which of the following principles?",options:["Trust but verify approach to network security","Never trust, always verify regardless of location or user identity","Trust is established once and maintained indefinitely","Only trusted users can access all resources"],correctAnswers:["Never trust, always verify regardless of location or user identity"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What is the role of 'audit logs' in cloud native security?",options:["To improve application performance by reducing overhead.","To manage user permissions effectively.","To track and record access and changes to resources for compliance and security monitoring.","To automate backup processes."],correctAnswers:["To track and record access and changes to resources for compliance and security monitoring."],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1}],f=["A","B","C","D","E","F","G","H"],x=1e3/h.length;function y(){let[e,t]=(0,a.useState)(0),[s,n]=(0,a.useState)(0),[y,w]=(0,a.useState)([]),[b,v]=(0,a.useState)(!1),[A,S]=(0,a.useState)([]),[j,N]=(0,a.useState)(!1),[k,C]=(0,a.useState)(0),T=t=>{let s=h[e];s.multipleAllowed?y.includes(t)?w(e=>e.filter(e=>e!==t)):y.length<(s.maxSelections||1/0)&&w(e=>[...e,t]):w([t])},z=h[e],q=z.multipleAllowed&&y.length>=(z.maxSelections||1/0),I=z.multipleAllowed?y.length!==z.maxSelections:0===y.length;return(0,i.jsxs)("div",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 min-h-screen pt-5 pb-5 flex items-center justify-center bg-[#0a0f18] bg-[radial-gradient(ellipse_80%_80%_at_50%_-20%,rgba(120,119,198,0.3),rgba(255,255,255,0))]",children:[(0,i.jsx)(o(),{id:"5aaa0a84c2479658",children:".bg-pattern{background-image:url(\"data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg width='100' height='100' viewBox='0 0 100 100' xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%3E%3Cpath d='M11 18c3.866 0 7-3.134 7-7s-3.134-7-7-7-7 3.134-7 7 3.134 7 7 7zm48 25c3.866 0 7-3.134 7-7s-3.134-7-7-7-7 3.134-7 7 3.134 7 7 7zm-43-7c1.657 0 3-1.343 3-3s-1.343-3-3-3-3 1.343-3 3 1.343 3 3 3zm63 31c1.657 0 3-1.343 3-3s-1.343-3-3-3-3 1.343-3 3 1.343 3 3 3zM34 90c1.657 0 3-1.343 3-3s-1.343-3-3-3-3 1.343-3 3 1.343 3 3 3zm56-76c1.657 0 3-1.343 3-3s-1.343-3-3-3-3 1.343-3 3 1.343 3 3 3zM12 86c2.21 0 4-1.79 4-4s-1.79-4-4-4-4 1.79-4 4 1.79 4 4 4zm28-65c2.21 0 4-1.79 4-4s-1.79-4-4-4-4 1.79-4 4 1.79 4 4 4zm23-11c2.76 0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5-5 2.24-5 5 2.24 5 5 5zm-6 60c2.21 0 4-1.79 4-4s-1.79-4-4-4-4 1.79-4 4 1.79 4 4 4zm29 22c2.76 0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5-5 2.24-5 5 2.24 5 5 5zM32 63c2.76 0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5-5 2.24-5 5 2.24 5 5 5zm57-13c2.76 0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5-5 2.24-5 5 2.24 5 5 5zm-9-21c1.105 0 2-.895 2-2s-.895-2-2-2-2 .895-2 2 .895 2 2 2zM60 91c1.105 0 2-.895 2-2s-.895-2-2-2-2 .895-2 2 .895 2 2 2zM35 41c1.105 0 2-.895 2-2s-.895-2-2-2-2 .895-2 2 .895 2 2 2zM12 60c1.105 0 2-.895 2-2s-.895-2-2-2-2 .895-2 2 .895 2 2 2z' fill='%23ffffff' fill-opacity='0.05' fill-rule='evenodd'/%3E%3C/svg%3E\")}"}),(0,i.jsxs)("div",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 w-full max-w-2xl p-4 sm:p-6 md:p-8 border bg-[#1a1f2e]/50 shadow-lg shadow-cyan-500/20 border-cyan-800 rounded-lg",children:[(0,i.jsx)("div",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 flex justify-center mb-6",children:(0,i.jsx)(d.default,{src:"/logo.svg",alt:"Quiz Logo",width:160,height:160,className:"rounded-3xl p-2 "})}),(0,i.jsx)("h1",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 text-3xl md:text-4xl font-bold text-center mb-6 text-transparent bg-clip-text bg-gradient-to-r from-emerald-400 via-cyan-500 to-blue-500 animate-gradient-text",children:"Overview of Cloud Native Security"}),(0,i.jsx)(r.N,{mode:"wait",children:b?(0,i.jsxs)(c.P.div,{initial:{opacity:0,scale:.9},animate:{opacity:1,scale:1},transition:{duration:.5},className:"text-center",children:[(0,i.jsx)("h2",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 text-2xl sm:text-3xl font-bold mb-4 sm:mb-6 text-green-300",children:"Quiz Completed!"}),(0,i.jsxs)("p",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 text-xl sm:text-2xl mb-4 sm:mb-6 text-cyan-300",children:["Your score: ",Math.round(s)," / ",1e3]}),(0,i.jsx)("p",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 "+"text-xl sm:text-2xl mb-2 ".concat(j?"text-green-300":"text-red-400"),children:j?"Congratulations! You passed with ".concat(k,"%"):"Sorry, you did not pass. You scored ".concat(k,"%")}),(0,i.jsxs)("div",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 mt-6 sm:mt-8 text-left",children:[(0,i.jsx)("h3",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 text-lg sm:text-xl font-semibold mb-4 text-cyan-300",children:"Question Summary:"}),h.map((e,t)=>(0,i.jsxs)("div",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 mb-4 sm:mb-6 bg-gray-700 bg-opacity-50 rounded-lg p-3 sm:p-4",children:[(0,i.jsxs)("p",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 font-medium mb-2 text-gray-100",children:[t+1,". ",e.question]}),(0,i.jsx)("div",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 mb-2",children:e.options.map((t,s)=>(0,i.jsxs)("p",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 "+"".concat(e.correctAnswers.includes(t)?"text-green-300":"text-gray-300"),children:[f[s],". ",t]},s))}),(0,i.jsxs)("p",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 "+"flex items-center ".concat(JSON.stringify(A[t].sort())===JSON.stringify(e.correctAnswers.sort())?"text-green-300":"text-red-400"),children:["Your Answer(s): ",A[t].map(t=>f[e.options.indexOf(t)]).join(", "),JSON.stringify(A[t].sort())===JSON.stringify(e.correctAnswers.sort())?(0,i.jsx)(l.A,{className:"ml-2 w-5 h-5"}):(0,i.jsx)(u.A,{className:"ml-2 w-5 h-5"})]})]},t))]}),(0,i.jsx)("button",{onClick:()=>{t(0),n(0),w([]),v(!1),S([]),N(!1),C(0),h=(0,g.A)(h)},className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 mt-4 sm:mt-6 p-3 sm:p-4 bg-cyan-600 hover:bg-cyan-700 rounded-lg text-lg font-semibold transition-all duration-300 text-white w-full",children:"Restart Quiz"})]},"results"):(0,i.jsxs)(c.P.div,{initial:{opacity:0,y:20},animate:{opacity:1,y:0},exit:{opacity:0,y:-20},transition:{duration:.5},children:[(0,i.jsxs)("div",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 mb-4 text-lg font-semibold  text-transparent bg-clip-text bg-gradient-to-r from-emerald-400 via-cyan-500 to-blue-500 animate-gradient-text",children:["Question ",e+1," of ",h.length]}),(0,i.jsx)("h2",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 text-xl sm:text-2xl font-bold mb-4 sm:mb-6 text-cyan-500",children:z.question}),(0,i.jsx)("div",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 grid grid-cols-1 sm:grid-cols-2 gap-3 sm:gap-4 mb-4 sm:mb-6",children:z.options.map((e,t)=>(0,i.jsxs)("button",{onClick:()=>T(e),disabled:q&&!y.includes(e),className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 "+"p-3 sm:p-4 rounded-lg text-left transition-all duration-300 ".concat(y.includes(e)?"bg-cyan-600 text-white":q?"bg-gray-600 text-gray-400 cursor-not-allowed":"bg-gray-700 hover:bg-gray-600 text-gray-100"),children:[(0,i.jsxs)("span",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 font-bold mr-2",children:[f[t],"."]})," ",e]},e))}),z.multipleAllowed&&(0,i.jsxs)("p",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 text-sm text-cyan-300 mb-4",children:["This question requires ",z.maxSelections," selections. You have selected ",y.length," out of ",z.maxSelections,"."]}),(0,i.jsx)("button",{onClick:()=>{let i=h[e],o=i.multipleAllowed?i.correctAnswers.every(e=>y.includes(e))&&y.length===i.correctAnswers.length:y[0]===i.correctAnswers[0];if(o&&n(s+x),S([...A,y]),e+1<h.length)t(e+1),w([]);else{let e=s+(o?x:0),t=e>=700;N(t),C(Math.round(e/1e3*100)),v(!0),t&&setTimeout(()=>{(0,m.A)({particleCount:100,spread:70,origin:{y:.6}})},500)}},disabled:I,className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 "+"w-full p-3 sm:p-4 rounded-lg text-lg font-semibold transition-all duration-300 ".concat(I?"bg-gray-700 cursor-not-allowed text-gray-400":"bg-cyan-600 hover:bg-cyan-700 text-white"),children:e===h.length-1?"Finish Quiz":"Next Question"})]},"question")}),(0,i.jsx)(p.A,{})]})]})}}},e=>{var t=t=>e(e.s=t);e.O(0,[6,379,441,517,358],()=>t(6181)),_N_E=e.O()}]);